<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>azure on BartekR</title>
    <link>https://blog.bartekr.net/categories/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in azure on BartekR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.bartekr.net/categories/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build your SQL Server VM using CdkTf</title>
      <link>https://blog.bartekr.net/2022/10/31/build-your-sql-server-vm-using-cdktf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.bartekr.net/2022/10/31/build-your-sql-server-vm-using-cdktf/</guid>
      <description>When I build infrastructure in Azure, I use terraform. I can&amp;rsquo;t force myself to use ARM templates, and I&amp;rsquo;m not yet convinced to use bicep. Terraform has flaws and problems, and HCL is not that intuitive initially, but after banging my head against the wall, we became friends.
Yet, some time ago, when I saw Pulumi on DevOpsLab - I knew I would have to try it. Using C# to create infrastructure was something I wanted to do a while ago with Farmer and F#.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read Data From Azure Blob Storage to Azure SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://blog.bartekr.net/2021/06/13/read-data-from-azure-blob-storage-to-azure-sql-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.bartekr.net/2021/06/13/read-data-from-azure-blob-storage-to-azure-sql-database/</guid>
      <description>In one of the projects, we store source files as JSON data on Azure Blob Storage. These files must be loaded into Azure SQL Database. We use a .NET code to perform this, but how could I load the files directly into Azure SQL Database?
The environment Nothing extraordinary: a default storage account bartekr01stacc configured with local redundancy (LRS) + SQL Database VariousExamples located within bartekr01 Azure SQL Server. The storage account has json-data-container container (set as private) and json-data-share file share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Yourself a Web App in Azure</title>
      <link>https://blog.bartekr.net/2021/02/28/build-yourself-a-web-app-in-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.bartekr.net/2021/02/28/build-yourself-a-web-app-in-azure/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: Recently (around 19th February 2021), the basic web app architecture got updated. The new version shows more possibilities, as it uses Azure Key Vault, Azure Monitor and introduces deployment slots.
 When you want to build an Azure-hosted web application that will use Azure SQL Database - it looks easy. You take a Basic Web App reference architecture, and you are set. It even has the ARM Template to deploy to have a working environment in just a few clicks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
